

Lucas Stahl

Libertyville, IL | Stahl1109@gmail.com

Marketing Manager

Ten plus years of experience working in marketing, sales and business development. Demonstrated ability to market new product/service lines and generate revenue. Territories encompassed the entire Chicagoland market. Self-starter, resourceful, logical and creative problem solver.

EDUCATION

- Southern New Hampshire University- Master's Degree in Communications: New Media and Marketing (August 2017)
- Illinois State University- Bachelors of Arts and Science, Major in Communications (May 2006)
- Northwestern University- Web Programming Certificate (Expected May 2018)

HIGHLIGHT OF SKILLS

Excellent project management Exceptional communication skills

Effective relationship builder Strong work ethic/professional demeanor

Experience in strategic planning Customer service centered

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Responsive Design, Git, JSON, jQuery, AJAX, Github, Firebase, Project Management, Windows, Mac, Microsoft Office, Design, Editing, Social Media, Blogging, Film editing (Premiere & Final Cut Pro), Adobe PDF, InDesign, Lightroom, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, WordPress, Salesforce and Workfront.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Northwestern Medicine Lake Forest Hospital - Lake Forest, IL

Senior Marketing Specialist

(08/15 - Present)

- · Project managed and developed marketing growth initiatives for orthopedics, neurosciences, pulmonary and cardiovascular service lines.
- Managed media marketing/advertising campaigns including social media tactics for Facebook.
- Digital marketing lead for north region, including email marketing, web content, SEO, Google Analytics and design.
- Managed marketing budgets for hospital based service lines, exceeding a guarter million.
- Designed and edited consumer facing material through Adobe Software (InDesign, Photoshop, and Illustrator) in addition to video production (Premiere).
- · Developed and managed communications for new product/service launches and brand campaigns.
- Project lead for sponsorships including BMW Championship, with a budget over \$150k.
- Increased overall hospital brand awareness and achieved targeted service line ROI.
- Digital lead for new hospital activation, specifically the launch of the new Lake Forest Hospital.
- Worked cross-functionally with digital, internal communications and media/public relations teams to coordinate B2B or B2C growth.

Physician Services Outreach Representative

(04/12 - 08/2015)

- Developed initiatives and successfully increased referrals in areas of oncology, neurology, primary care, orthopedics, sports medicine, pulmonary, ENT, rehabilitation, imaging/diagnostics, medical devices, lab, and women's health.
- Facilitated physician-to-physician networking between employed physicians and private physicians to gain referrals.
- Ambassador for the Philanthropy department to raise funds for charitable organizations.
- Hosted networking events for both employed physicians and private physicians.



Lucas Stahl

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE CONT'D

Odyssey Hospice Care - Arlington Heights, IL

Account Executive

- Built relationships with long term care facilities and physicians resulting in referrals.
- Developed and secured 19 additional multilevel contracts with facilities and hospitals in 2011 generating referrals and new revenue to the terri-
- Managed & directed the clinical team for ventilation patients.
- Increased referral base from averaging 1-3 patients per month in 2010 to 9-12 patients per month in 2011.

Vitas Innovative Hospice Care - Chicago, IL

Sales Representative

(08/2009 - 11/2010)

(11/2010 - 04/2012)

- Developed and implemented quarterly sales plans.
- Increased referral base in a very challenging territory from 1-2 patients per month in 2009 to 5-7 patients per month in 2010.
- Developed and secured 10 new contracts which tripled referrals and had a significant impact on revenue.

Physiotherapy Associates, Inc. - Chicago, IL

Marketing and Sales Representative

(02/2007 - 08/2009)

- Designed and implemented a local lead generation program resulting in significant new referral source relationships and \$600,000 in additional annual revenues.
- Developed and implemented strategic annual marketing plans for 23 facilities with annual revenues of \$12 million.
- Managed staff in all phases of marketing, sales, budgeting and monthly goals.
- Worked with operations to review profit and loss statements.
- Increased physician referral base by 10% over a two-year period.
- Website design, content management and events coordinator.

Patient Services Manager (12/2005 - 02/2007)

www.lucasstahl.com



linkedin.com/in/lucasstahl



@LucasStahl11



github.com/Stahlwalker